<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Study Schedule</string>
    <string name="log_body_temperature">Log Body Temperature</string>
    <string name="check_normal_range">Check Normal Range</string>
    <string name="mechanism_of_fever">Mechanism of Fever</string>
    <string name="handling_fever">Handling Fever</string>
    <string name="normalRangeText">
Temperature control (thermoregulation) is part of a homeostatic mechanism
that keeps the organism at optimum operating temperature, as the temperature
affects the rate of chemical reactions. In humans, the average internal
temperature is 37.0 °C, though it varies around this point by 0.5 to 1 °C.
However, no person always has exactly the same temperature at every moment of
the day. Temperatures cycle regularly up and down through the day, as controlled
by the circadian rhythm. The lowest temperature occurs about two hours before
the person normally wakes up. Additionally, temperatures change according to
activities and external factors.
¥n ¥n
Normal human body temperature varies slightly from person to person and
by the time of day. Consequently, each type of measurement has a range of normal
temperatures. The range for normal human body temperatures, taken orally, is
36.3-37.3 °C. This means that any oral temperature between 36.3 and 37.3 °C is
likely to be normal. The normal human body temperature is often stated as 36.5–
37.5 °C. In adults a review of the literature has found a wider range of 33.2–
38.2 °C for normal temperatures, depending on the gender and location measured.
¥n ¥n
Reported values vary depending on how it is measured: oral (under the
tongue): 36.4-37.2 °C, internal (rectal, vaginal): 37.0 °C. A rectal or vaginal



measurement taken directly inside the body cavity is typically slightly higher
than oral measurement, and oral measurement is somewhat higher than skin
measurement. Other places, such as under the arm or in the ear, produce
different typical temperatures. While some people think of these averages as
representing normal or ideal measurements, a wide range of temperatures has
been found in healthy people. The body temperature of a healthy person varies
during the day by about 0.5 °C with lower temperatures in the morning and higher
temperatures in the late afternoon and evening, as the body needs and activities
change. Other circumstances also affect the body temperature. The core body
temperature of an individual tends to have the lowest value in the second half
of the sleep cycle; the lowest point, called the nadir, is one of the primary
markers for circadian rhythms. The body temperature also changes when a person
is hungry, sleepy, sick, or cold.
</string>
</resources>
